<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>linux on Getting Started</title>
    <link>https://alemorm.github.io/ucsf-radiology-getting-started/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in linux on Getting Started</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>alejandro.moralesmartinez@ucsf.edu (Alejandro Morales Martinez)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>alejandro.moralesmartinez@ucsf.edu (Alejandro Morales Martinez)</webMaster>
    
	<atom:link href="https://alemorm.github.io/ucsf-radiology-getting-started/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://alemorm.github.io/ucsf-radiology-getting-started/page/gitedu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>alejandro.moralesmartinez@ucsf.edu (Alejandro Morales Martinez)</author>
      <guid>https://alemorm.github.io/ucsf-radiology-getting-started/page/gitedu/</guid>
      <description>Git Resources Git is a powerful versioning control system that allows you to keep track of changes for your files. Additionally, it allows for collaboration with other people on the same project. It is recommended to develop your work using a versioning tool such as git.
 Quick Git Intro      Peder Larson Group:  Git Tutorial Software Development for Scientists    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://alemorm.github.io/ucsf-radiology-getting-started/page/linuxedu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>alejandro.moralesmartinez@ucsf.edu (Alejandro Morales Martinez)</author>
      <guid>https://alemorm.github.io/ucsf-radiology-getting-started/page/linuxedu/</guid>
      <description>Linux Resources The radiology servers are running a Linux distribution and therefore it is highly recommended to get familiar with Linux.
 Note: Keep in mind that the servers run tcsh by default, which is very similar to bash with some slight differences. You can type bash into any terminal to start using bash.
  Beginner&amp;rsquo;s Guide to the Bash Terminal      Linux cheatsheet  A collection of useful Linux commands      MIT Missing Semester  For a more advanced dive into these concepts, the MIT Missing Semester is another great resource to learn about linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://alemorm.github.io/ucsf-radiology-getting-started/page/serverinfo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>alejandro.moralesmartinez@ucsf.edu (Alejandro Morales Martinez)</author>
      <guid>https://alemorm.github.io/ucsf-radiology-getting-started/page/serverinfo/</guid>
      <description>Radiology Server Access All of the imaging and medical patient data is located within UCSF Radiology encrypted Linux servers. Here is how to access them:
List of Radiology servers Please refer to the full list of Radiology servers (requires UCSF login) for a comprehensive list of servers grouped by CPU and GPU resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://alemorm.github.io/ucsf-radiology-getting-started/page/sshinfo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>alejandro.moralesmartinez@ucsf.edu (Alejandro Morales Martinez)</author>
      <guid>https://alemorm.github.io/ucsf-radiology-getting-started/page/sshinfo/</guid>
      <description>SSH The SSH (Secure Shell) protocol is an encrypted communication protocol for networking. It is a highly versatile and powerful tool that serves as the main way to access the servers.
 Setup Depending on the operating system you are using, follow these options:
Mac and Linux users  Open a terminal and type the following:  ssh username@servername.radiology.ucsf.edu -L 9XXX:localhost:9XXX For the above command make sure to replace the username with your own, the servername with any of the listed server names (requires UCSF login) and the 9XXX with a number above 9020 There will be a prompt for your UCSF password    PC users  Use WSL, PuTTY, Cygwin or any other SSH tool:  Use servername.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://alemorm.github.io/ucsf-radiology-getting-started/page/vncinfo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>alejandro.moralesmartinez@ucsf.edu (Alejandro Morales Martinez)</author>
      <guid>https://alemorm.github.io/ucsf-radiology-getting-started/page/vncinfo/</guid>
      <description>VNC Unlike SSH, VNC allows you to access a virtual display of the servers. This lets you browse through the file system and open visual applications such as Matlab and a web browser in a virtual operating system. Follow these steps to start a VNC session:
 Download and install VNC Viewer. Once installed you will need to SSH to the server to which you will VNC into and type the following command into a terminal:  myvncserver Towards the bottom of the output, take note of the last number as that will be the display number you will need to access the VNC server.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>